# **Indranil Halder**

#### SOFTWARE ARCHITECT · FULL STACK ENGINEER · JAVASCRIPT ENTHUSIAST

Balurghat, Dakshin Dinajpur, 733101, West Bengal, India

□ (+91) 6294716288 | Sindranilhalder.dev@gmail.com | Aindranildeveloper.in | Dindranildeveloper | Dindranildeveloper

# **SUMMARY**

MERN Stack developer JavaScript enthusiast who has a predilection for design and enjoys working on projects where approaching design and development as co-dependent processes can lead to more innovative solutions and a better overall product experience for human beings.

# SKILLS

Frontend React, Redux, NextJS, GatsbyJS, Angular, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Material UI, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

**Back-end** Node JS, Express, MongoDB, Django, REST API, GraphQl, PostgreSQL, Strapi CMS

**Programming** JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C++, Mardown, LaTex

**DevOps** Docker, Kubernetes, Azure **Languages** English, Bengali, Hindi

## **EXPERIENCE**

Private AI Toronto, Canada

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Jun. 2022 - Present

• Currently working as a Frontend Engineer and worked on several projects and tasks from building frontend applications and maintaining the

- website to deploying web applications to Cloud.

  Created the Web Demo from scratch which calls a custom backend API and displaying the data in different formats in the documentation.
- Created complete CI/CD pipeline with GitHub Actions and Deployed the Web Demo in Production.
- Created the Customer Portal from Scratch with React and Typescript.
- Contributed and Implemented to the privacy layer of ChatGPT, PrivateGPT.
- Created the initial UI, Entity Selection, Markdown Output, Code Block Syntax Highlighting.

Meta (formerly Facebook)

Remote

FULL STACK ENGINEER May. 2023 - Present

- Made contribution to the Bengali version of React Documentation.
- Translated the tutorial page to Bengali and continuously reviewing the documentation.

Coder's Gyan Remote

FULL STACK ENGINEER Oct. 2021 - Present

- Building the full stack web application for Coder's Gyan Youtube Channel.
- Helping in building new projects and find new project ideas.
- · Updating the old code and fix bugs in the existing codebase of projects.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### **DJ Events**

FULL STACK ENGINEER

- Full Stack Application for finding latest DJ and musical Events.
- Tech Stack: NextJS, Strapi CMS, Tailwind CSS.

## **ProShop E-Commerce Web App**

FULL STACK ENGINEER

- MERN Stack ECommerce web application with user and admin dashboard, authentication system, user reviews and other functionality.
- Tech Stack: React, Redux, Bootstrap, Node JS, Express, MongoDB.

#### **Dev Connector**

FULL STACK ENGINEER

- · MERN Stack Social Media Application with Authentication, User Comments, Create, Read, Update and Delete Posts functionality.
- Tech Stack: React, Redux, Sass, Node JS, Express, MongoDB.

Indranil Halder · Résumé

#### **DevSpace Blog**

#### FRONTEND ENGINEER

- · Static Blog Website which fetches data from local markdown files.
- Tech Stack: NextJS, Tailwind CSS.

#### **Memories**

FULL STACK ENGINEER

- MERN Stack Social Media Application with Authentication, User Comments, Create, Read, Update and Delete Posts with Image upload functionality.
- Tech Stack: React, Redux, Material UI, Node JS, Express, MongoDB.

#### **Support Desk**

FULL STACK ENGINEER

- A Support Desk System for different products with Create, Read, Update and Delete product Issues with separate note taking functionality with every product issue.
- Tech Stack: React, Redux, Bootstrap, Node JS, Express, MongoDB.

#### **Project Management App**

FULL STACK ENGINEER

- A simple project management application with CRUD functionality.
- Tech Stack: React, Redux, Bootstrap, Node JS, Express, GraphQL, MongoDB.

#### **Github Finder Application**

FRONTEND ENGINEER

- A simple React Application to serach GitHub users and show the data in a nicer way.
- Tech Stack: React, Context API, Tailwind CSS, DaisyUI.

# **CERTIFICATES**.

## **Next JS Dev To Deployment**

Online

 Udemy
 Dec. 2022 - Jan. 2023

• Built DJ Events, a platform for managing musical events, and DevSpace blog which fetches data from local markdown files.

#### **MERN E-Commerce From Scratch**

Online

UDEMY Aug. 2021 - Dec. 2022

• Built a Full Stack E-Commerce Application from start to finish with React, Redux, NodeJS, Express and MongoDB.

# MERN Stack Front To Back: Full Stack React, Redux and NodeJS

Online

UDEMY Jun. 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Built a Full Stack Social Media Application from start to finish with React, Redux, NodeJS, Express and MongoDB.

# **MERN Stack Online Bootcamp**

Online

LEARN CODE ONLINE Jun. 2021 - Dec. 2021

• Built an E-Commerce application from start to finish with MERN Stack.

# **EDUCATION**

#### University of Gour Banga

Malda, West Bengal, India

M.Sc. In Physics

Nov. 2020 - Present

· Made a computer program for understanding the Scrondiger's Equation In Quantum Mechanics.

## **Balurghat College**

Balurghat, Dakshin Dinajpur, West

Bengal, India

B.Sc. In Physics Jun. 2017 - Oct. 2020

• Participated in District and State level Science Exhibition and stood 2nd in District Level Exhibition.

Indranil Halder · Résumé